Guide to the Samson Raphaelson Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Manuscripts by Raphaelson
  - Subseries III.1: Fiction
    - Skylark [Play], 1939-1942, ( Reviews (clippings) (Box 20)
    - [Skylark] Goodbye Lady [Play], ( Playscript, draft, ) (Box 20)
    - [Skylark] Man and Wife [Play], ( Playscript (draft, carbon copy) (Box 20)
    - The Smiling Lieutenant [film], 1931, ( Scenario (Xerox copy) (Box 21)
    - Song At Twilight (Short Story - Hilda Benson), Good Housekeeping, 1947, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 21)
    - Sticks and Stones [Play], ( Playscript, drafts & notes, ) (Box 21)
    - Stopover In Chicago [Short Story], ( Typescripts (carbon copies) (Box 21)
    - Stopover In Chicago [Short Story], Cosmopolitan, 1951, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 21)
    - [Stopover In Chicago] Stopover, ( Television script (mimeographed copy) (Box 21)
    - The Store [Play] See: Mike Miller [Play] (Box 21)
    - Streamlined Heart [Short Story] See: OVERSIZE See also: Skylark [Play] (Box 21)
    - [Suspicion] Before the Fact [film], 1941, ( Scenario (Xerox copy) (Box 21)
    - [Suspicion] Before the Fact [film], 1940, ( Xerox copy of screenplay, ) (Box 21)
      [Screenplay by Boris Ingster & Nathanael West]
    - [Suspicion] Before the Fact [film], 1940, ( Xerox copy of screenplay, ) (Box 21)
      [Screenplay by Joan Harrison]
    - [Suspicion] Before the Fact [film], 1941, ( Typescript film treatment (Xerox copy], ) (Box 21)
    - Suspicion [film], ( Miscellaneous, ) (Box 21)
    - Take It Away (Poem), ( Typescript, ) (Box 22)
    - Terrible As an Army With Banners [Short Story], Romance, 1920, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 22)
    - That Lady In Ermine.[film], 1948, ( Scenario (Xerox copy) (Box 22)
    - Thelma Play [Play] See: Fable [Play] (Box 22)
    - There's No Law a Man Has To Understand His Wife [Short Story] See: Agent Meets Lady [Short Story] (Box 22)
    - A Thousand Kisses [film] See: Casanova [Film, not produced] (Box 22)
    - Samson Raphaelson Three Screen Comedies, 1981-1984, ( Review & catalog listing, ) (Box 22)
    - Trouble In Paradise [film], 1932, ( Scenario (Xerox copy) (Box 22)
      [Edited for publication]
    - Trouble In Paradise [film], 1932, ( Scenario (Xerox copy) (Box 22)
      [Final editing for publication]
    - Trouble In Paradise [film], ( Typescript for publication (Xerox copy) (Box 22)
    - Trouble In Paradise [film], ( Typescript of interview, ) (Box 22)
      [See:OVERSIZE]
    - Trouble In Paradise [film], 1972-1985, ( Miscellaneous, ) (Box 22)
    - Two Little People [film], ( Typescript film treatment, ) (Box 22)
    - "Untitled Play" See: [Bunny] "Untitled Play" (Box 22)
    - White Man [Play], 1936, ( Playscript (carbon copy) (Box 22)
    - Who Am I [Short Story], 1947/1948, ( Typescripts (carbon copies) (Box 22)
    - Who Am I [Short Story], Good Housekeeping, 1948, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 22)
    - Who Am I [Short Story], ( Miscellaneous, ) (Box 22)
    - Who Could Ask For Anything More? [Play- Musical], 1943, ( Notes & outlines, ) (Box 22)
    - The Winner [Short Story], Good Housekeeping, 1948, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 23)
    - Without Love [film], 1943, ( Screenplay (mimeograph copy) (Box 23)
    - The Wooden Slipper [film], ( Typescript film treatment (mimeograph copy) (Box 23)
    - The Wooden Slipper [Play], 1934, ( Programs & reviews, ) (Box 23)
    - Young Love [Play], 1928-1947, ( Programs, ) (Box 23)
    - Young Love [Play], 1928-1947, ( Reviews & clippings, ) (Box 23)
    - Young Love [Play], ( Miscellaneous, ) (Box 23)
    - Young Man [film], 1972, ( Screenplay, ) (Box 23)
    - Young Love [Play] See also: Israeli-American Play [film] (Box 23)
    - Young People Musical [Play], ( Outlines & notes, ) (Box 23)
    - Untitled & miscellaneous (Box 23)
  - Subseries III.2: Non-Fiction
    - Achilles and Aeneas -- Two Conceptions Of a Hero [Student Essay], 1920, ( Typescript, ) (Box 24)
    - Antigone and Medea -- a Brief Comparison Of the Characters Of Two Women [Student Essay], 1920, ( Typescript, ) (Box 24)
    - [Book Review Of] How To Read a Film by James Monaco, ( Typescript, ) (Box 24)
    - [Book Review Of] How To Read a Film by James Monaco, ( Notes, ) (Box 24)
    - [Book Review Of] How To Read a Film by James Monaco, ( Galley proofs, corrected, ) (Box 24)
    - [Book Review Of] How To Read a Film by James Monaco, Film Comment, 1977, ( Printed copy, ) (Box 24)
    - [Book Review Of] A Preface To Life by Edwin Justus Mayer [Article], The Nation, 1923, ( Tearsheet, ) (Box 24)
    - [Book Review Of] "Thirty Years Of Theatrical Enterprise" in American Writing Today [Article], 1949, ( Clipping with 2 xerox copies, ) (Box 24)
    - The Cher Spectacular [Article] See: Sonny, Cher, and Me [Article] (Box 24)
    - A Comparison Of the Religion In Homer's Iliad and the Religion Presented By Plato Through Socrates in The Apology [Student Essay], 1920, ( Typescript, ) (Box 24)
    - For the Love Of Liv [Article], ( Typescript (Xerox copy) (Box 24)
    - For the Love Of Liv [Article], ( Notes, ) (Box 24)
    - For the Love Of Liv [Article], ( Tearsheets with 2 xerox copies, ) (Box 24)
    - For the Love Of Liv [Article], American Film, 1977, ( Printed copy, ) (Box 24)
    - For the Love Of Liv [Article], ( Miscellaneous, ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], 1980, ( Manuscript, first draft, ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], 1980, ( Typescript, "carbon of 1st typed", ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], 1980, ( Typescript, corrected, ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], 1980, ( Typescript, "corrected copy", ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], 1980, ( Typescript, "first typed", ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], 1980, ( Typescript, "master copy", ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], 1981, ( Typescript, setting copy, ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], ( Correspondence about article, ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], 1977-1980, ( Notes, ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], ( Galley proofs, revised, ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], The New Yorker, 1981, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 24)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical Article On Ernst Lubitsch], The New Yorker, 1981, ( Printed copy, ) (Box 24)
    - The Glittering Snake [Article - Television Criticism], ( Typescript (Xerox copy) (Box 25)
    - The Glittering Snake [Article - Television Criticism], ( Notes, ) (Box 25)
    - The Glittering Snake [Article - Television Criticism], Film Comment, 1979, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 25)
    - The Glittering Snake [Article - Television Criticism], Film Comment, 1979, ( Printed copy, ) (Box 25)
    - Griselda As a Heroine [Student Essay], 1920, ( Typescript, ) (Box 25)
    - Hollywood Parties In the 30s and 40s [Article], ( Typescript (incomplete) (Box 25)
    - The Human Nature of Playwriting [Book], 1947-1955, ( Correspondence, ) (Box 25)
    - The Human Nature of Playwriting [Book], 1948-1955, ( Correspondence with students, ) (Box 25)
    - The Human Nature of Playwriting [Book], ( Clippings: reviews, etc., ) (Box 25)
    - The Human Nature of Playwriting [Book], ( Promotion, ) (Box 25)
    - Kol1ek Teddy [Autobiography] Edited by Raphaelson [Book], ( Original manuscript Typescript drafts, ) (Box 26)
    - Kollek, Teddy [Autobiography] Edited by Raphaelson [Book], ( Notes & discards, ) (Box 27)
    - The Last Time I Saw Lubitsch [Biographical Article] See: Freundschaft [Biographical Article about Ernst Lubitsch] (Box 27)
    - Notes on Lumber Jacks, ( Typescript notes, ) (Box 27)
    - On My Word Of Honor As An Adjunct Professor [Article On Teaching], [1977], ( Typescript, ) (Box 27)
    - On My Word Of Honor As An Adjunct Professor [Article On Teaching], [1977], ( Promotion, ) (Box 27)
    - On My Word Of Honor As An Adjunct Professor [Article On Teaching], American Film, 1977, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 27)
    - On My Word Of Honor As An Adjunct Professor [Article On Teaching], Columbia, 1983, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 27)
    - On My Word Of Honor As An Adjunct Professor [Article On Teaching], American Film & Columbia, ( Printed copies, ) (Box 27)
    - [On Ruth Orkin, photographer] [Article], 1974, ( Typescript & Xerox copy, ) (Box 27)
    - People We Like. (Obituary Article on James M. Cain), Film Comment, 1978, ( Printed copy, ) (Box 27)
    - Personal To Sonny Bono [Article] See: Sonny, Cher, and Me [Article - Television Criticism] (Box 27)
    - Random Notes [for American Film Magazine] [Article], 1976, ( Typescript drafts, ) (Box 27)
    - Smothers Brothers [Article - Television Criticism], 1975, ( Manuscripts, ) (Box 27)
    - Sonny, Cher, and Me [Article - Television Criticism], 1974-1976, ( Drafts, ) (Box 27)
    - Sonny, Cher, and Me [Article - Television Criticism], 1974-1980, ( Clippings, ) (Box 27)
    - Sonny, Cher, and Me [Article - Television Criticism], American Film, 1977, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 27)
    - Sonny, Cher, and Me [Article - Television Criticism], American Film, 1977, ( Printed copy, ) (Box 27)
    - That Lady in Bergman [Article - Film Criticism on Ingmar Bergman & Liv Ullman], 1976, ( Typescripts, ) (Box 27)
    - That Lady in Bergman [Article - Film Criticism on Ingmar Bergman & Liv Ullman], ( Notes, ) (Box 27)
    - That Lady in Bergman [Article - Film Criticism on Ingmar Bergman & Liv Ullman], Film Comment, 1976, (Tearsheets ) (Box 27)
    - That Lady in Bergman [Article - Film Criticism on Ingmar Bergman & Liv Ullman], Film Comment, 1976, ( Printed copy, ) (Box 27)
    - That Lady in Bergman [Article - Film Criticism on Ingmar Bergman & Liv Ullman], 1977, ( Miscellaneous, ) (Box 27)
    - Youth Grows Young [Essay on Education], Century, 1922, ( Printed copy, ) (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 27)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Papers
  - Financial & business papers, 1932-1975 (Box 28)
  - Interviews: Columbia University Oral History Project, 1959 (Box 28)
  - Interviews: "Creativity with Bill Moyers" [Television show], 1981 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous., 1931-1978 (Box 28)
  - Writers Guild of America Laurel Award, 1977 (Box 29)
  - Lubitsch, Ernst (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 29)
  - Universities: Columbia University - Teaching, 1976-1982 (Box 29)
  - Universities: University of Illinois - Student and teacher (Box 29)
  - Universities: University of Illinois - The Siren [Contributions by Raphaelson], 1916- 1917 (Box 29)
- Series V: Oversize Material
  - Sunseries V.1: Fiction Manuscripts by Rahaleson
    - The Happiness of Rebecca [Short Story], Hearst's International Magazine, 1918, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 30)
    - The Jazz Singer [Play], 1925/1926, ( Reviews (clippings mounted on scrapbook pages) (Box 30)
    - Streamlined Heart [Serial], The Saturday Evening Post, 1939, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 30)
    - Trouble in Paradise [film], 1980, ( Typescript of interview (Computer print-out) (Box 30)
  - Subseries V.2: Miscellaneous Material
    - Universities: Columbia University - Teaching, Honorary Degree, 1981 (Box 30)
- Series VI: Original Inventory
  - Original handwritten inventory of the collection and the envelopes which contained the manuscripts, with many notes added by Mr & Mrs Raphaelson (Box 30 & 31)
- Series VII: Arranged Correspondence
  1990 Gift
  - A (Box 32)
  - Accent on youth (Box 32)
  - After the ball. (Box 32)
  - American Film [Journal] (Box 32)
  - The Atlantic Monthly (Box 32)
  - B (Box 32)
  - Boolie (Box 32)
  - Bunny Lake is missing (Box 32)
  - C (Box 32)
  - Crawford, Cheryl (Box 32)
  - D (Box 32)
  - Dahlberg, Gilda & Bron (Box 32)
  - E (Box 32)
  - F (Box 32)
  - G (Box 32)
  - Gold, Michael (Box 32)
  - The group theatre, inc. (Box 32)
  - H (Box 32)
  - Hayward, Leland, Inc. (Box 32)
  - Here we are, alone together (Box 32)
  - Hilda Crane/Hilda Benson (Box 32)
  - Hitchcock, Alfred (Box 32)
  - The human nature of playwriting (Box 32)
  - I (Box 33)
  - Israeli correspondence (Box 33)
  - Jason (Box 33)
  - The jazz singer (Box 33)
  - Kane, Robert (Box 33)
  - King with umbrella (Box 33)
  - Knopf, Alfred (Box 33)
  - Kupferberg, Audrey (Box 33)
  - L (Box 33)
  - Last day in Paris (Box 33)
  - Writers Guild of America Laurel award (Box 33)
  - Lawrence, Seymour (Box 33)
  - Lubitsch, Ernst (Box 33)
  - M (Box 33)
  - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures (Box 33)
  - N (Box 33)
  - National Star (Box 33)
  - The New Yorker (Box 33)
  - P (Box 34)
  - The perfect marriage (Box 34)
  - Playboy (Box 34)
  - A prince in disguise (Box 34)
  - R (Box 34)
  - Rough Treatment (Box 34)
  - S (Box 34)
  - Salisbury, Leah (Box 34)
  - Sheba musical (Box 34)
  - Skylark (Box 34)
  - The Smithsonian Institution (Box 34)
  - T (Box 34)
  - That lady in ermine (Box 34)
  - Three screen comedies (Box 34)
  - Trouble in paradise (Box 34)
  - U (Box 34)
  - W (Box 34)
  - White, Minor (Box 34)
  - White man (Box 34)
  - The winner (Box 34)
  - Wood, Audrey (Box 34)
  - The wooden slipper (Box 34)
  - Writers Guild of America (Box 34)
  - Young love (Box 34)
  - Young man (Box 34)
- Series VIII: Manuscripts and Documents
  Mostly contracts
  - Accent on Youth [Play] (Box 35)
  - Angel [film] (Box 35)
  - Bunny Lake is Missing [Play] (Box 35)
  - The Burning Secret [film] (Box 35)
  - Cinderella Was a Vamp [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - Cow (Photograph) (Box 35)
  - Counterfeit Heaven [film] (Box 35)
  - Domestic Episode [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - Eyes for No Other Woman [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - The Greatest Idea in the World. [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - He Wanted to Marry a Rich Girl. [Short Story] See: Marry for Money [film] (Box 35)
  - Her First Affair. [Short Story] See: After the Ball. [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - Here We Are, Alone Together. [Play] (Box 35)
  - Hilda Crane. [Play] (Box 35)
  - A Hollywood Fable. [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - I'm Mavis, the Irish Girl. [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - It Was a Pleasure. [Short Story] See: Rough Treatment. [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - Jason. [Play] (Box 35)
  - The Jazz Singer. [Play] (Box 35)
  - Kollek, Teddy: Autobiography (Box 35)
  - Last Day in Paris. [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - Letter to the Editor [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - Lizette. [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - Madness of Man. [Two part story] (Box 35)
  - Main Street to Broadway. [film] (Box 35)
  - Marry for Money. [film] (Box 35)
  - Malinda Knew It Was Wrong. [Short story] (Box 35)
  - Malinda Went Through With It. [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - The Middle-Aged Freshman. [Short Story] (Box 35)
  - My Boy. [film] (Box 35)
  - Old Love. [film] See: Accent on Youth [Play] (Box 35)
  - The Perfect Marriage. [Play] (Box 35)
  - Portrait of Jenny. [Play] (Box 35)
  - A Rose Is Not a Rose. [Short Story] See: Letter to the Editor. [Short Story] (Box 36)
  - Rough Treatment [Short Story] (Box 36)
  - Sheba musical. [Play] (Box 36)
  - Skylark. [Play] (Box 36)
  - Stopover in Chicago. [Short Story] (Box 36)
  - Suspicion. [Film] (Box 36)
  - Three Screen Comedies. [Book] (Box 36)
  - What Is Glamour. [Article] (Box 36)
  - White Man. [Play] (Box 36)
  - Who Am I. [Short Story] (Box 36)
  - The Wooden Slipper. [Play] (Box 36)
  - Young Love. [Play] (Box 36)
- Series IX: Miscellaneous Papers
  - Writers Guild of America Laurel Award, 1977 (Box 36)
  - Universities: Columbia University, 1961-1982 (Box 36)
  - Financial and Business. Papers, 1942-1978 (Box 36)
  - Xerox copies of the notes on the manilla envelopes which contained the manuscripts (Box 36)
- Series X: 1992 Gift
  - Subseries X.1: Correspondence
    - Correspondence: A - Z (Box 37)
  - Subseries X.2: Manuscripts, Documents & Related Materials
    - Accent on Youth [Play] (Box 37)
    - All In the Family [TV Show] (Box 37)
    - Angel [Film] (Box 37)
    - Ann Preaskill [Yankee Doodle Dandy] [Autobiographical article] (Box 37)
    - Anniversary [Play] (Box 37)
    - Antonioni, ( Teaching notes, ) (Box 37)
    - Boolie [Play] (Box 37)
    - The Boudoir Diplomat [Film] (Box 37)
    - Brooks Atkinson Story [Autobiographical article] (Box 37)
    - Bunny - "Untitled Play" [Play] (Box 37)
    - Call of the Redwoods [Film] (Box 37)
    - Carole [Short Story] (Box 37)
    - Casanova [Film] (Box 37)
    - Children [Play] (Box 37)
    - Children's Book [Story or Book] (Box 37)
    - Children Save World [Story] (Box 37)
    - Citizen [Film?] (Box 37)
    - Coctail Marriage [Film] (Box 37)
    - Essay on G. J. N. [George Jean Nathan] [Article] (Box 38)
    - Fable [Eleventh Commandment] [End of the World] [Shirley] [Play] (Box 38)
    - For the Love of Liv [Article] (Box 38)
    - Freundschaft [Biographical article on Ernst Lubitsch] (Box 38)
    - From Main St. to B'way [film] (Box 38)
    - The Going Up of David Lev [TV Movie] (Box 38)
    - Grandma [Story] (Box 38)
    - Harlem [Play] (Box 38)
    - Harrity-Raphealson Comedy [Play] (Box 38)
    - Heaven Should Have Waited a Little Longer [Article] (Box 38)
    - Helen Morgan Story [film] (Box 38)
    - Henry VIII [film] (Box 38)
    - Here We Are, Alone Together [Play] (Box 38)
    - Hilda Crane [Play] (Box 38)
    - Hitchcock, Alfred [Notes for story] (Box 38)
    - Hitler [Film] (Box 38)
    - Home, Sweet Home (Play & Short story) (Box 38)
    - Honey [Play] (Box 38)
    - The Human Nature of Playwriting [Book] (Box 38)
    - Israeli-American Screenplay [Film] (Box 39)
    - Israeli Play [Play] (Box 39)
    - Jason [Play] (Box 40)
    - The Jazz Singer (Play, Film, & Short story) (Box 40)
    - The Land of the Free [Play] (Box 40)
    - Lie Story (Play or Film) (Box 40)
    - Love at 80 [Play] (Box 40)
    - Lunt-Fontanne Play [Play] (Box 40)
    - The Man Who Wrestled Hemingway [Story] (Box 40)
    - Mr. Pin Prick (Murder of Oswald Pin Prick) [Story] (Box 40)
    - Moonlight and Roses [Film] (Box 40)
    - Mother How Could You [Play] (Box 40)
    - My Friend Leo [Play] (Box 40)
    - October Noon [Play] (Box 40)
    - On My Word of Honor As an Adjunct Professor [Article] (Box 40)
    - One in a Billion [ Guitar] [Short Story] (Box 40)
    - Passion Over the Counter [Play] (Box 40)
    - Playwriting notes (Box 40)
    - Rough Treatment [Short Story] (Box 40)
    - Sheba Musical [Play] (Box 40)
    - Shop Around the Corner [Film] (Box 40)
    - Six Approaches to Creating a Picture [Article] (Box 40)
    - The Store [Mike Miller] [Play] (Box 40)
    - Suspicion [Film] (Box 40)
    - Texas Story [Last Aristocrat] [Short Story] (Box 40)
    - That Lady in Bergman [Article] (Box 40)
    - Three Maples [ At Three Maples] [Play] (Box 40)
    - Three Screen Comedies [Book] (Box 40)
    - Trouble in Paradise [Film] (Box 40)
    - Vernon [Play] (Box 40)
    - Vinnie [Another Hollywood Fable] [Short Story] (Box 40)
    - White Man [Play] (Box 41)
    - Who Am I? [Short Story] (Box 41)
    - The Whore Next Door [Play] (Box 41)
    - Why Can't They Eat Bread (Story) (Box 41)
    - The Wooden Slipper [Play] (Box 41)
    - Young Love [Play] (Box 41)
    - Young Man [film] (Box 41)
    - Your Mistress Is Your Best Friend After All [Article] (Box 41)
    - Misc. notes & ideas [Fiction] (Box 41)
    - Misc. notes & ideas [Nonfiction] (Box 41)
  - Subseries X.3: Miscellaneous Papers
    - Audio equipment (Box 41)
    - Clippings (Box 41)
    - Financial and Medical (Box 41)
    - Interviews (Box 41)
    - Interviews: "Creativity With Bill Moyers" [TV Show] (Box 41)
    - Music Score: Leslie Bridgewater, "Old Love" (Box 41)
    - Universities and Teaching (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 41)